Adrian Zambrano

Profile

I'm a Lead Designer and UI Developer experienced in solving User experience issues, Implementing Design Systems and Maintaing best practices in Web Applications regarding modular design, Agile principles, and scalability. I've spent the last 6 years learning & Improving my user experience and technical development practice with different teams and projects in different organizations.

I'm also familiar with **Front-End Development constraints** and I am able to fill the comunication gap between designers and developers in a team.

Experience

Metalsa

UX Lead 2018 - Current I work as a **Lead UX Designer** and **UI Developer** at Metalsa, building web and mobile applications from scratch. Reviewing **primary user research**, wireframing, and **usability cases** for best practices. In charge of delivering **high-fidelity coded applications** to the development team and implementing best practices within the technology, usually **Angular 10+** or React. Worked in Industry 4.0 applications, Purchasing Processes & External Visits.

InverCap

UI Designer 2015 - 2018

I worked as UI Designer as the main responsible for designing and coding e-mail in HTML and CSS using IBM Watson with a more than 2 million client reach and web design using **HTML5**, **CSS3** & **JavaScript** coding languages for the development of more than 50 Landing Pages. Had experience elaborating informative video reels and animations.

EBCOMM

Web designer 2014 - 2015

I had the role of WordPress web designer and got the opportunity to polish my basic front-end knowledge. In charge of contacting and working with brand users of Eternity Diamonds, Ghiberti and Tigretienda. Learned about social media administration and helped achieve a reach growth of 25%.

Education

Google

UX Certificate 2021 - 2022 UX design process may vary from project to project. Properly completing the design process from beginning to end is my end goal with this certificate, including: **Empathizing with users**; Defining user pain points; Coming up with ideas for design solutions; Creating wireframes, mockups, and prototypes; Testing designs through **usability studies**; **Iterating** on designs based on feedback.

UANL University

Design Graduate 2011 - 2015 Graduated as a graphic designer I found my passion for developing visual concepts with self-taught programming technologies and bringing ideas into real-life applications.

Skills

Figma Git Sass InVision

Angular SVN VS Code React